# Vanessa Jade CantosMacRury

Apprentice Software Developer

#### **Personal Info**

Phone

07889 248614

E-mail

vjcmacrury@gmail.com

# Skills

**Communication Skills** 

**Expert** 

Telephone manner

Expert

Organisational Skill

Expert

Customer Service

Expert

Windows and Mac OS

**Proficient** 

#### **Software**

MS Word

Excellent

MS Excel

Expert

MS Powerpoint

Expert

MS Outlook

Competent

HTML5

Advanced beginner

Self-motivated apprentice software developer, seeking to channel passion for web development into delivering coding excellence for Infographics UK Ltd. Improved and updated surgery website (using rudimentary HTML and CSS skills) and all social media accounts, ensuring that all links are working and content are recent. Created a WordPress website for existing bed and breakfast with minimal online presence, which resulted in 10% increase of B&B bookings every summer season, 90% of which come through the website. Currently studying Cyber Security with FutureLearn and Building Websites from Scratch with Codecademy.

# **Skills Summary**

#### IT | Customer Service Helpdesk Experience

- Acted as single point of contact for phone calls and emails from staff regarding IT issues and queries and for patients who needed help accessing online services
- Took full ownership of inbound calls, seeing customers through with detailed solutions tailored specifically for their individual case
- Improved and updated surgery website (using HTML and CSS) and all social media accounts, ensuring that all links are working and content are recent
- Liaised with Western Isles IT Helpdesk, EMIS and Microtech Support when software and hardware problems arise
- Responsible for troubleshooting simple software issues that did not need escalating to centralised Helpdesk
- Provided support and training for staff to ensure that they complete annual training on confidentiality and security of data and resolving systems problems
- Trained new and existing staff as necessary on computer applications
- Updated protocols, processes and documents (e.g.: Locum Handbook)
- Completed basic cyber security training and communicated lessons learned to other members of staff
- Created a WordPress website for existing bed and breakfast with minimal online presence, which resulted in 10% increase of B&B bookings every summer season, 90% of which come through the website.

## **Excellent Communication Skills and Telephone Manner**

- Delivered focused and exceptional customer service in accordance with the Guest Services Vision and Mission Statement
- Took ownership of guest concerns, by following-up and ensuring complaints are logged and resolved to the guest's satisfaction
- Fielded enquiries pertaining to front desk services and general information
- Wrote a research paper on *Transcending NIMBYism: Communicating towards* greater cooperation
- Contributed a section in the academic book, Wilderness Protection in Europe

#### **Organisational Skills**

- Created the organisational structure of a team of Guest Admin Officers onboard the Voyager of the Seas in its maiden voyage to Asia, which resulted in the ship eventually leaving the Port of Singapore on time - the first Royal Caribbean ship to actually meet the deadline
- •Standardised our patient recall system, patient notes summary system and care home visit process, which resulted in a much smoother and efficient transfer of information

#### **Microsoft Office Applications**

•Created a colour-coded, macro-powered Excel spreadsheet for the IT department onboard a cruise ship to assist them in troubleshooting problems at the Guest Services desk. The spreadsheet cross-referenced each computer, user, application and problem and increased productivity by 10%

Advanced beginner

#### **Education**

2012-09 - 2013-10

#### **University of Brighton**

MSc Environmental Assessment and Management

Pass with Merit

2001-06 - 2005-03

#### **Ateneo de Manila University**

AB Major in Social Sciences Minor in German Studies 3.21 GPA

## Courses

2018-04 - present

Codecademy - Build Websites from Scratch

2018-01 - present

FutureLearn - Introduction to Cyber Security

2017-04 - 2017-04

Pitman Highland - Audio Transcription Levels 1 and 2

### **Interests**

Web design - creating content using online platforms like Canva

Web development - practising my coding skills by tweaking existing WordPress templates using HTML5 and CSS3

# Languages

**English - Certified** 

Fluent

Filipino

Fluent

German - certified

Proficient

#### **Experience**

#### 2013-10 - IT Lead | Reception | Dispensary

2018-02 South Uist Medical Practice

- Acted as single point of contact for phone calls and emails from staff regarding IT issues and queries and for patients who needed help accessing online services
- Ensured the provision of efficient reception and dispensing service

#### 2014-03 - Part-time Enterprise Worker

2015-04 *Cothrom* 

2009-05

- Travelled throughout the Outer Hebrides to draw together the experience of community organisations, agencies and individuals and to support individual young people, igniting their passion for enterprise on the islands
- Engaged with individual community land trusts, community representatives and the CnES Skills & Enterprise Team by phone, email and in-person

#### 2012-10 - Part-time German Speaking New Accounts Professional

2013-06 American Express Brighton Office

- Ensured that credit card applications are processed on time
- Maintained working knowledge of products and promotions

# 2010-06 - Guest Administration Officer | Senior Guest Services 2012-06 Officer | Guest Services Officer | Telephone Operator

Royal Caribbean International

- Expedited ship clearance and avoided fines through accurate collection and preparation of customs/immigration reports in all ports of call
- Maintained working knowledge of customs / immigration regulations

# 2007-11 - German Technical Support Representative Level 1

InterTouch Malaysia | Docomo InterTouch Philippines

- Acted as the single point of contact for phone calls and emails from staff regarding IT issues and queries
- Received, logged and managed international guest/hotel enquiries and (troubleshooting) requests from guests and hotel staff
- 1st Line support conducted troubleshooting of IT related problems from software to hardware and escalated to 2nd and 3rd line when necessary
- Calmed irate customers, restored company-customer relation, and applied appropriate resources for efficient problem resolution

# 2006-09 - **German Travel Expense Accountant (TEA)**

2007-11 IBM Business Services

- Ensured that claims comply with IBM Germany process
- Created a more manageable claim tracking system for each TEA
- Communicated with German-based business professionals by email regarding travel expenses

# 2005-04 - **German | English Customer Service Associate – Refunds**2006-02 **Team**

eTelecare Global Solutions

- Provided excellent customer service to American Express international clients while protecting company interests by doing a first-level investigation of possible fraudulent claims
- Applied appropriate resources for efficient problem resolution especially in emergency cases